布达佩斯
Budapest.
下一站 布达佩斯
The next stop's Budapest.
布达佩斯是下一站
Budapest is the next stop.
布达佩斯
Budapest.
车票 女士们
Tickets, ladies.
欧 给你
Oop, here you go.
- 这是我的 - 还有我的
- Here's mine. - And mine.
- 还有我的 - 给你
- Mine, too! - Here you go!
谢谢你 年轻人
Thank you, young man.
噢天 我讨厌伪装成这样
Man, I hate wearing disguises.
这高跟鞋简直要了我的命
These heels are killing me.
好了 冷静点
Okay, take it down a notch.
不要让人类警惕我们
We don't want to alarm the humans.
嘘 Drac
Psst. Drac.
我 要 吓死了
I'm about to und freak out!
你是一只可爱的小猫咪
You're a nice kitty.
我是一只小猫咪
I'm und kitty-cat.
喵 喵
Meow. Meow!
不 不 别又是这个小丑
Oh, no, not this clown again.
晚上好 旅客们
Good evening, travelers.
我是Abraham Van Helsing教授
I am Professor Abraham Van Helsing.
没错 Van Helsings家族的一员
Yes. One of the Van Helsings.
几个世纪以来 我的家族一直在保护人类
For centuries, my family has protected humanity.
免受邪恶怪兽的伤害
from the evils of monsters.
所以你们可以相信我 我告诉你们
So you can believe me when I tell you,
有怪兽藏在你们中间
there are monsters hiding amongst you!
但不要害怕
But fear not,
因为我是专家 我知道怎样才能把这些野兽赶走
for I am a professional, and I know how to flush out.
把它们的身份揭晓在众人面前
these beasts and bring them into the light!
糟了 火
Fire bad!
哇
Whoa!
抱歉了 伙计们
Sorry, guys.
最终是我 第一个杀死了Dracula
Finally! First I kill Dracula,
然后杀光了其余的怪兽
and then the rest of the monsters!
你们为什么一直这样做
Why do you keep doing this?
你的爸爸 你的爷爷 你的曾曾祖母
Your dad, your grandfather, your great-great-granny…
他们全被我打败了
I defeated them all.
什么时候你们Van Helsings才能学会放下仇恨
When will you Van Helsings ever learn to let go of the hate?
永不 因为你 是一个怪兽
Never! Because you, monster, are a…
吱吱 吱吱
Eh, squeak, squeak.
什么 怎么是一只老鼠
What? A mouse?
啊
Ahhh!
你逃不掉的 黑暗之王
You can't run from me, Prince of Darkness!
我会永远追捕你
I will hunt you for all eternity!
我发誓 在毁灭掉你之前我将永不停止
I swear I will never rest until I destroy you…
还有
And…
每一个
Every…
其他的
Other…
怪兽
Monster… Ow!
这是唯一一件
If it's the last thing…
我
I…
要做的
Ever…
事情
Do!
天 那家伙真烦人
Boy, that guy is annoying.
也许某天会有这样一个地方
Maybe one day there will be a place.
怪兽们到那儿可以远离这一切
where monsters can go to get away from it all,
度个假
take a vacation.
也许还能结婚 谁知道呢
Who knows, maybe even get married.
岂不美哉
Wouldn't that be something?
《精灵旅社3：疯狂假期》
欧 婚礼到底什么时候开始
Oh, when is this thing starting?
你把他们弄哭了 Wayne
Aw, you made them cry, Wayne.
除了这个小家伙
All except this little one. Coochie-coochie…
这是Sunny 她不会哭
That's Sunny. She doesn't cry.
但她会咬人
She bites.
这是对你非常重要的时刻 Carl
This is a very special moment, Carl.
你美丽的新娘随时都会走上红毯
Any second, your beautiful bride is going to walk right down the aisle.
不 Drac 她不会来的
Oh, no, Drac, she's not coming.
噢 别担心
Oh, don't worry.
Mavis和她在一起呢 我相信一切都在掌控之中
Mavis is with her. I'm sure everything is under control.
Mavey 一切都还好吗
Mavey, is everything under control?
呃 还好 只是她有点婚前紧张的小问题罢了
Um, yep, just a slight case of pre-wedding jitters.
啊
Ahhh!
没事儿 我这儿一切都好
Yep, everything is fine here.
Lucy 试着放松一下
Please try to relax, Lucy.
放心 我会帮你打理好一切
I've taken care of everything.
保证给你一个完美的婚礼
The wedding is going to be perfect.
不是这个问题
It's not that.
我怎么才能确定 我做了正确的选择呢
Just, how do I know I'm doing the right thing?
我想我明白你的感受
I know just how you feel.
嫁给Johnny那天 是我人生中最幸福的一天
The day I married Johnny was the best day of my life,
但我却超级紧张
but I was so nervous.
可没我紧张
Not as nervous as I was.
你真该看看我爸爸当时的样子 他紧张得不得了
And you should have seen my dad. He was a mess.
那天晚上我甚至都不愿从我的棺材里出来
I wouldn't get out of my coffin that night.
但他知道一切都是命中注定的
But he knew it was meant to be.
无论你来自哪里
It doesn't matter where you come from.
或是多么的与众不同 这些都不重要
or how different you are.
心动这种事 一生中只有一次
A Zing only happens once in your life,
你一定要珍惜
and you have to cherish it.
噢
Aw.
你说的好有道理 谢谢你
You're right! Thank you!
好啦 好吧 好吧
Okay. All right. Okay.
噢 呃 好的吧
Oh. Uh… Okay.
我愿意
I do.
你听到那个声音了吗
Do you hear that?
听见了 我以为我们把他关在他的房间里了
Yes. I thought we locked him in his room.
我们是把他关好了 没错啊
We did!
哇噢哇噢
Whoa! Whoa!
嗨 妈咪 嗨 外公
Hi, Mom. Hi, Papa.
- Dennis！- Dennis！
- Dennis! - Dennis!
我听到Tinkles在哭 所以我们就把他放出来了
Tinkles was crying, so we let him out.
啊
Ahhh!
Tinkles 坐下
Tinkles, sit!
啊 当初是谁出的馊主意让Dennis养了个小狗
Ah. Whose idea was it to let Dennis have a puppy?
呃 好像是您的主意吧
Um… Yours?
没错
Right.
可怜的Tinkles
Poor Tinkles.
Dennis…
听我说宝贝 我知道你很爱Tinkles
Look, honey, I know you love Tinkles,
但我们不能带着我们的狗狗
but we're not allowed to bring our dogs…
我是说 我们的宠物 到处跑
Uh… I mean, our pets everywhere.
好吗
Okay?
好的
Okay.
- ∮ 我沉浸在爱河里 ∮ - ∮ 我爱上了一个怪兽 ∮
- ∮ I'm in love ∮ - ∮ I'm in love with a monster ∮
这里是DJ Jazzy Johnny
DJ Jazzy Johnny in the house.
接下来 让我们有请这对幸福的新婚夫妇 Prickles夫妇
It's time to welcome the happy couple, Mr. and Mrs. Prickles!
噢
Aw!
新娘新郎邀请大家
The bride and groom invite everyone.
一起加入舞池
to join them on the dance floor.
∮ 永远永远 ∮
∮ Always and forever ∮
想一起跳个舞吗
Care to dance?
∮ 和你在一起的每一个瞬间 ∮
∮ Each moment with you ∮
那是她吗
Is that her?
噢 你瞧啊
Ooh! Watch out now.
她身上的每一处都太完美了
She got stitches in all the right places.
她不会是你的亲戚吧Frank
Okay, there's no way that is related to you, Frank.
没错她是我右胳膊主人的表亲
No, she's my right arm's cousin.
啊 噢
Ay! Oh!
- 喔 - 阿 我看出来了
- Oh! - Ah! I see it now.
Frank希望我来见你
Frank wanted me to meet you.
我们的胳膊是表亲 隔了两代
We're arm cousins, twice removed.
当然 当然
Of course.
这肱二头肌我走到哪都能认出来
I'd recognize that bicep anywhere.
他认为 既然我们俩都单身 说不定能一见如故
He thought, since we're both single, we might hit it off,
或许我们能来一场约会
maybe go on a date?
约会 噢
"Date"? Oh!
好吧 额 那个
Well, eh, it's just that, eh…
喔
Whoa!
DJ台可是个神圣的地方 别捣乱
The DJ booth is a sacred space!
我爱这首歌
I love this song!
你不喜欢吗
Don't you?
Dracula
Dracula?
噢 他去哪了
Oh, where'd he go?
Dracula？
Dracula?
怎么了 Drac 你不喜欢她吗
What's the matter, Drac, you didn't like her?
无意冒犯 但是你不能鸡蛋里挑骨头
No offense, but you can't be too picky.
你已经100年没有约会过了
You haven't had a date in 100 years.
嘿 伙计们 很感谢你们的关心 但没办法
Look, guys, I appreciate your concern, but it's not up to me.
一个人只能心动一次 我心动过了
You only Zing once, and I did.
时代在变 老兄
Times have changed, buddy.
现在甚至可以在手机上跟某个人相爱
You can even find someone to Zing with on your phone now.
什么 真的
What? Really?
噢 不 不 不
Oh. Oh, no, no, no.
我太忙了
I'm far too busy.
我有Mavis和Dennis 还有旅馆 「给我血 给我血”
I have Mavis and Dennis and the hotel, and bleh, bleh-bleh.
额 伙计们 你们听见了吗
Um, did you guys hear that?
他刚才真的在说 「给我血 给我血”
He actually said, "Bleh, bleh-bleh."
我从来不说 「给我血 给我血」
I don't say, "Bleh, bleh-bleh"!
额 额 我在寻找爱情
Eh, uh, I'm looking for a Zing.
好的 更换手机铃声
Okay. Changing phone ring.
不 不 我想要一次约会
No, no. I'm looking for a date.
不 不 不
No, no, no.
我想和某个人出去见面
I want to meet someone.
你在跟我开玩笑嘛
Are you kidding me right now?
你听不明白吗 我想要次约会
Don't you get it? I want to go on a date!
我好孤单
I'm lonely.
我明白了 你想要火腿肠
You want baloney.
什么 看看那头发 天呐
What? Look at that hair. Come on.
额 眼睛太多了
Ah. Too many eyes.
眼睛太少了
Too few eyes.
对长触角的不感兴趣
Not into tentacles.
匹配成功
"Match found"?
不 不 不
No, no, no!
最为重要的
First things first.
我去
Whoa!
我可不是闹着玩
I'm not into games.
你最好有份工作 而且我的猫必须喜欢你
You'd better have a job, and my cats have to like you.
噢 不
Oh, no.
噢 天呐 不
Oh, whoa, no.
老爸
Dad?
噢 Mavis 噢
Oh! Mavis! Oh.
额 你在这干什么
Uh, what are you doing here?
我刚在检查蜜月套房 听到有动静
I was just checking on the honeymoon suite, and I heard something.
噢 对不起 我的小甜心
Oh, I'm sorry, my little bedbug.
我刚刚在收拾阁楼
I was just cleaning the attic.
太脏了 呃 是的
It's so dirty, ah, yes…
- 那是谁 - 你在打电话吗
- Who is that? - Are you on the phone?
什么 这个吗 我打算找个女佣
What, this? I was just trying to find a maid.
- 来帮我收拾这些乱七八糟的 - 找个女佣
- to help me with the mess. - A maid?
你以为我是谁
Who do you think…
谢谢 我会看看你的资料
Thank you, I'll check your references.
然后再打给你 再见
and get back to you. Goodbye!
老爸
Dad.
别跟我遮遮掩掩的了
Stop trying to hide it from me.
遮遮掩掩 谁 什么意思 我
Hide? Who? I mean, what? Me?
没错
Yes.
而且我知道你在干什么
And I know what it is.
额 真的吗
Uh… Really?
你工作得太辛苦了
You're stressed out from working too hard.
噢
Oh!
好吧 对对
Okay, yes.
被你发现了
You got me.
旅社太大了 你懂的
It's a big hotel, you know?
不可能都照顾得过来
Can't get to everything.
你怎么样
But what about you?
你自己也一直很忙啊
You're pretty busy yourself.
我知道 虽然看起来我们一起工作的时间更多了
I know. It seems like now that we're working together more,
却见到彼此更少了
we're seeing each other less.
啊 对 你说的都对
Ah. Yeah. You're absolutely right.
我工作得太多了 你工作得也太多了
I am working too much, you're working too much.
我们真的该休息下 比如就现在开始
We should really take a break, starting right now.
晚安慢走不送
Night-night.
我还在呢
I'm still here!
噢
Aw.
噢 嘿 亲爱的
Oh! Hey, honey.
你准备好今晚的
You ready for.
约会了吗
date night?
噢
Aw.
没关系 亲爱的
That's okay, sweetheart.
你睡吧
You rest.
你知道吗 爸爸说的对
You know, Dad's right.
我们是需要休息一下了
We need a break.
我们需要都聚在一起 像个家一样
We need to all be together again, like a family.
像以前那样
Like we used to.
你是否因工作过量而精疲力竭
Are you overworked and stressed out?
你是否需要阖家出行走遍万水千山
Do you need some family time?
你是否是个怪兽
Are you a monster?
那你就需要
Then you need a vacation,
一次怪兽旅行
a monster vacation.
∮ 出发吧 出发吧 出发吧 ∮
∮ Sail away, sail away, sail away ∮
欢迎乘坐小妖精航空
Welcome aboard Gremlin Air.
喂喂喂
Ah!
先生们女士们
Ladies and gentlemen,
请看向机舱的前方
please direct your attention to the front of the cabin.
为了您的安全 请解开安全带
For your safety, please unbuckle your seat belts.
啊
Ooh.
在航行中 我们很有可能会经历客舱失压
In the likely event we experience a sudden drop in cabin pressure,
我们将为您提供氧气面罩
oxygen will be provided.
行李需要我帮您放起来吗先生
Can I stow that for you, sir?
好的 谢谢了
All right. Thanks.
啤酒 饮料 矿泉水
Beverages. Snacks. Beverages.
花生 瓜子 八宝粥
Beverages. Snacks.
八-宝-粥
Beverages.
啊
Ahhh!
- 咖啡需要吗 - 太感谢了
- Coffee? - That would be lovely.
Mavis 求你了 你这简直就是折磨我
Mavis, please, you're torturing me.
你知道我讨厌惊喜
You know I hate surprises.
这可是个有趣的惊喜
This is a fun surprise.
哪里有趣了
There are no fun surprises.
能不能先告诉我我们要去哪儿
Just tell me where we're going.
以及为何我们在飞机上啊
Why are we on a plane?
我们自己明明就可以飞的啊
We can fly, you know.
在我们那个年代 人们都是坐火车
Back in my day, people took trains.
那才叫品味
Now, that's classy.
对对对 爸 四十个小时挤在一个小隔间里最有品位了
Sure, Dad. Forty hours in a closet-sized room.
尤其是你和Bernie叔叔在里面抽难闻的雪茄
with you and Uncle Bernie and his smelly cigars,
还争论着哪个男人更帅
arguing who was more attractive,
Cleopatra还是Nefertiti
Cleopatra or Nefertiti.
Nefertiti
Nefertiti.
行了 谢谢你 爸爸
Okay, Dad, thank you.
Mavis Mavis 这可真是个惊喜
Mavis, this is such an amazing surprise!
我等不及和我最爱的人们一起去度假了
I can't wait to spend time with the people I love most.
但是我求求你 告诉我一下目的地
But I beg of you, tell me where we're going!
不了 我已经准备好了一切 你不用操心
Nope. I've taken care of everything, so you don't need to worry.
你最近压力太大了
You've been so stressed out lately.
是时候歇歇了
It's time for you to relax.
好多了吧
Now, isn't that better?
好吧 你说得对
Oh, yes.
真舒服
So relaxed.
我去看看那个谁
I'm gonna go check on you-know-who.
我去去就回
I'll be right back.
我得去趟厕所
I have to go to the bathroom.
嗨 你看到那个了吗
Hey, did you see that?
Dennis去厕所了
Dennis went to the bathroom!
额…好吧
Uh… Okay.
喂 你在哪
Psst. Hey, where are you?
你在这啊 Tinkles
There you are, Tinkles.
别担心 我们不会把你一个人丢在家里的
Don't worry, we'd never leave you home alone.
好了 伙计们 你们可以
Okay, folks, you're free to move.
在机舱里随意走动 因为我们
about the cabin, as we have.
已经开始降落
started our descent.
周末有什么计划吗 Bill
So, any big plans for the weekend there, Bill?
你懂的 和往常一样
Oh, you know, the usual.
要带孩子们去踢足球
Got to take the kids to soccer.
啤酒 饮料 矿泉水
Snacks. Beverages.
花生 瓜子 八宝粥
Snacks. Beverages. Snacks.
女士们先生们 我们已经到达目的地
Ladies and gentlemen, we've arrived at our destination,
百慕大三角洲
the Bermuda Triangle.
噢
Ooh!
欢迎来到百慕大三角洲
Welcome to the Bermuda Triangle,
你们将在这里展开一场惊心动魄的游轮之旅
where you'll embark on a monster cruise of a lifetime.
一艘游轮
A cruise?
惊喜吧
Surprise!
噢 不 你… 不
Oh, no, you… No.
但这只是一个在水上的旅馆
But it's just like a hotel on the water.
我只是觉得你需要一个假期
I just figured you need a vacation.
不用再为其他人的假期操心
from running everyone else's vacation.
你几乎不出旅馆 自从
You've barely been out of the hotel since…
自从妈妈去世以后
Well, since Mom died.
但这是一次我们全家一起
But this is a chance to make new memories,
创造新的回忆的机会
with all of us.
和Dennis一起
With Dennis.
- 船 - 船
- Boat! - Boat!
是谁带大了你这么棒的女儿
Who made you such an amazing daughter?
是你
You.
没毛病
That's right!
我真是个了不起的老爸
What a father I am.
来吧 Denisovich 我们上船吧
Come on, Denisovich, let's get cruising!
呀
Yay!
哇
Wow!
来 笑一个
Okay. Smile.
谢谢
Thank you.
噢
Ow!
宠物禁止入内
"No pets allowed"?
不妙
Uh-oh.
完美
Perfect.
欢迎登船 你们好
Welcome aboard. How are you doing?
- Dennis 快点 - 很高兴见到你
- Dennis, come on. - Nice to see you.
很棒的衬衫
Oh, lovely shirt. Yes.
噢 你好 欢迎登船
Oh, hello. Welcome aboard.
这是Bob
Uh, this is Bob.
说你好 Bob
Say hi, Bob.
你好 Bob
"Hi, Bob."
噢 我的天啊 Griffin
Oh, my gosh, Griffin.
我 我好激动啊
I'm, like, so excited.
这是我去过最棒的旅馆
This is, like, the nicest hotel I've ever been to.
可不是
Yeah!
天 这也太炫酷了
Man, this is amazing!
有这么多好玩的
There's so much to do!
奥运标准泳池
Olympic-size swimming pool…
自助餐
All-you-can-eat buffet…
全套服务的SPA
Full-service spa…
哇 我要做个海草磨皮
Whoo! I'm gonna get me a seaweed rewrap!
哇 听上去这里能做的所有项目
Wow, it sounds like everything we can do.
在我们自己的旅馆都能做到
at our hotel!
除了它是在水上！
Except on the water!
噢 啊
Ooh! Ah!
哇
Wow!
宝贝 你安排得太棒了
You nailed it, honey.
你老爸会爱死这一切的
Your dad is going to love this!
有史以来最棒的假期
Best summer vacation ever!
之后的行程会更棒的
Wait till you see the itinerary.
哇噢
Oh!
真棒
That's nice.
Frank 我讨厌烟花
Frank, "fire bad." Remember?
噢 对 没错 但是 也许你会在这邮轮上找到
Oh, yeah, right, but, uh, maybe you'll find.
属于你自己「不一样的烟火」 也说不定呢
your own fireworks on the cruise, huh?
Frank 这不是艘爱情的小船好吗
It's not the Love Boat, Frank.
我来这里 只是为了和家人共度好时光的
I'm just here to have fun with my family.
什么鬼
Huh?
哈
Ha!
大家好啊
Ahoy there!
欢迎登船
Welcome aboard!
哇 那是谁啊
Whoa! Who is that?
我是船长Ericka
I am Captain Ericka.
是的 没错 我是人类 但不要因此而对我有成见噢
And, yes, I'm human. But don't hold that against me.
能有幸邀请大家来到史上第一个怪兽邮轮
I could not be more excited to have all of you on board.
真的让我 太激动啦
our first-ever monster cruise!
哇
Whoo-hoo!
老爸 你还好吗
Dad? Are you okay?
Eeny feeny fanny foonyah wah wah？
Eeny feeny fanny foonyah wah wah?
啊 不 他心脏病发作了
Oh, no! He's having a heart attack!
Drac 不会吧
Drac? Not likely.
只有在他心脏插一根木棍 才能让他犯心脏病
Yeah, the only heart attack that can hurt him is with a wooden stake.
那肯定就是中风了
It must be a stroke!
其实 我觉得可能是因为她
Actually, I think it might be her.
喂 别乱戳 先生 我站在这呢
Ow! Watch where you're pointing, mister, I'm right here.
你总是贴着我站
You always stand so close to me.
怪瘆人的
It's creepy.
怪兽们在黑暗中隐姓埋名地生活了太久了
For so long, monsters were hiding, living in the shadows,
你们不再需要这样生活了
but not anymore!
你们可以站起来挥舞你们的手臂 爪子 或触角
You've stood up and waved your hand or claw or tentacle.
大声宣告 我们在这里 我们就是毛茸茸的 我们有权利长得吓人
and said, "We're here, we're hairy, and it is our right to be scary!"
此时此刻 让我们狂欢庆祝吧
Now it's time to celebrate!
在到达目的地前的旅程里
You'll enjoy gourmet dining, thrilling adventures,
你们将品尝到珍馐美馔 体验激动人心的冒险
and nonstop entertainment,
还有 永无休止的娱乐项目
all on the way to our final destination,
那座沉没的岛屿 已不再沉默
the lost city that isn't lost anymore,
亚特兰提斯
Atlantis!
噢耶
Oh, yeah!
喔 喔
Whoo-hoo!
哇噢 这些鱼是杂技演员耶
Whoa! The fish are acrobats!
他们是鱼技演员
They're fishcrobats!
你们好吗
Hello. How y'all doing?
你好
So…
您一定就是举世无双的Dracula了
You must be the one and only Dracula.
人家好不容易才把你盼来呀
I have waited so long to meet you.
哇 你真的是不会变老啊
Wow, you really don't age, do you?
我死都想要你那好皮肤
I would kill for your skin.
Eh doobeeday shoolah eh koobeeday？
Eh doobeeday shoolah eh koobeeday?
噢 你在讲精灵语啊
Oh. You're speaking Transylvanian.
人家一直好想学呢
Oh. Always wanted to learn.
Uh，eh doobeeday shoolah koobeeday？
Uh, eh doobeeday shoolah koobeeday?
- Eh koobeeday。- Koobeeday
- Eh koobeeday. - Koobeeday.
Doolah-day shoolah koobeeday
Eh doobeeday shoolah koobeeday.
噢 真是门浪漫的语言
Oh, such a romantic language.
不知道为什么 带一点口音
You know, there's just something about an accent.
总是会让男人听上去很有头脑
that makes a man sound so intelligent.
Alibooboo
Alibooboo.
他在讲精灵语
That's Transylvanian right there.
他说的是 很高兴认识你
He's saying it's nice to meet you.
那 我也 alibooboo
Well, then "alibooboo" to you as well.
- Alibooboo Alibooboo - Drac Drac 振作点
- Alibooboo. Alibooboo. - Drac! Drac, snap out of it.
等会儿 我早就想这么干了
Wait. I've always wanted to do this.
醒醒吧 醒醒吧 Drac
Wake up! Wake up, Drac!
振作点呀
Snap out of it!
喂 行了行了
Hey, cut it out!
喂 哥们 你还好吗
Hey, buddy, you okay?
不 不太好
No, not okay.
不太好
Not okay!
我 我
I… I…
我
I…
动心了
Zinged.
∮ 我去到摩托车店 说 卖了它 ∮
∮ I went to the moped store, I said, "Sell it" ∮
∮ 售货员说 嗨 你的预算是多少 ∮
∮ Salesman's like, "What up? What's your budget?" ∮
∮ 我说 我实际上对摩托车一无所知 ∮
∮ And I'm like, "Honestly, I don't know nothin' about mopeds" ∮
∮ 他说 那我知道给你哪辆了 跟我来 ∮
∮ He said, "I got the one for you, follow me" ∮
∮ 噢 太酷了 ∮
∮ Ooh, it's too real ∮
∮ 一个镀铬的玻璃 我不需要挡风玻璃 ∮
∮ A chromed-out mirror, I don't need a windshield ∮
嗯
Mmm!
∮ 这真是美妙的一天 ∮
∮ It's a lovely day ∮
- 噢 - 噢
- Ooh! - Oh!
快看 快看
Check that out!
啊
Ah!
走你
Here we go.
嗯 秀色可餐噢
Mmm, yummy.
啊
Ah!
∮ 再会 ∮
∮ Auf Wiedersehen ∮
∮ 非常感谢 ∮
∮ Danke schoen ∮
爸爸
Papa.
儿童俱乐部
"Kids Club."
什么是儿童俱乐部
What's a kids club?
Whee！
Whee!
- 鱼 - 是的 亲爱的
- Fish. - That's right, dear.
我还是不太明白
I'm still not sure I understand.
你会专门照顾我的孩子们 一整天
You take my kids, all day, on purpose?
鱼
Fish.
是的
That's right.
你到底还有什么不明白的
What exactly don't you understand?
- 为什么 - 嘘
- Why? Ow! - Shh.
这样他们可以玩得很开心 你也可以玩得开心
So they can have a great time, and you can have a great time.
鱼
Fish.
噢 不要担心 你可以在晚上把它们接回去
Oh, don't worry, you get them back at the end of the day.
鱼
Fish.
噢 好吧 聊胜于无
Oh, well. That's better than nothing.
噢 噢
Oh. Oh!
那么
So…
我们现在做什么呢
What do we do now?
我觉得 我们想做什么都可以
I think we do whatever we want.
什么都可以吗
"Whatever we want"?
什么都可以
Whatever we want.
真的什么都可以吗
什么都成
Whatever we want!
- 别走 救命 - 想干啥就干啥
- Stop! Help me! - Whatever we want.
- 我们想干嘛就干嘛 - 我们想干嘛就干嘛
- Whatever we want. - Whatever we want.
噢 你好
Oh, hi. Hello.
你们都好吗
How y'all doin'?
- 噢 - 晚上好 船长
- Oh. - Good evening, Captain.
你好 噢 我的天哪
Well, hello. Oh, my goodness.
啊
Ah!
你介意 呃 抬一下尾巴吗
Would you mind, uh, lifting your tail? You know…
噢 当然
Oh! Certainly.
非常感谢
Okay. Thank you so much.
噢 你好
Oh, hello.
欢迎乘船
Welcome aboard.
你是对的 曾祖父
Ugh! You were so right, Great-Grandfather.
怪兽们真恶心
Monsters are disgusting!
他们禽兽不如
They're animals!
我马上到
I'll be right there.
Dracula在船上吗
Dracula, is he on board?
是的 我见到他了 面对面 呃
Yes. I saw him. Face-to-face. Ugh!
我对他很客气
I was so nice to him.
他那苍白的脸和愚蠢的傻笑
That pale face of his and his goofy smile,
炫耀着他的尖牙
showing off his fangs.
啊 跟你对我说的一模一样
Argh, it's just like you taught me!
简直是可怕至极好吗
It's even worse than I feared!
是那个不祥之夜
It was that fateful night that I realized.
我意识到 人类无法永远打败怪兽
a human could never defeat a monster.
但是 我不能看着家族传承断送在我手里
But I wouldn't let our family legacy die.
所以 我开始找办法
And so, I began to search for an answer.
最后终于让我在古书中 找到一份无敌破坏乐谱
And I saw it in an ancient text, an instrument of destruction.
破坏力强到可以摧毁亚特兰提斯里
so powerful it destroyed Atlantis,
一整座城的怪兽
a whole city of monsters.
它在废墟深处 等待着
And there, deep within the rubble, it lay, waiting.
我一直都在找这座失落之城
Endlessly, I searched for the lost city.
随着时间流逝 我的身体越来越令我失望
Time passed, and my body began to fail me.
噢 这是一个悲伤的故事 Ericka
Oh, it was so sad, Ericka.
先是我的肝 再是我的脾
First my liver, then my spleen,
紧接着是肾 两颗
followed by a kidney or two.
还有我美丽的金发
Then my golden locks.
但这并不会阻止我
But I wouldn't let that stop me.
我用机器取代败坏的器官
I replaced my failing organs with technology!
啊 哈
Ha-ha!
看看我现在
And look at me now.
嗯 哼
Mmm-hmm!
噢 真是改良版的自己
Oh, girl, it's an improvement, really.
嗯… 当然
Um, sure.
终于啊 120年后的今天 让我找到了亚特兰提斯
And now, after 120 years, I have finally found Atlantis.
噢 别管这么多了
Oh, forget about all this!
我现在就去干掉Dracula
Let me get rid of Dracula right now.
离他那么近的 我本来可以直接
I was so close to him, I could've just…
不 不 不
No, no, no!
我们要按计划来
We have to stick to the plan.
把那些怪兽引到亚特兰提斯
Lure the monsters to Atlantis,
拿到无敌破坏乐谱
retrieve the instrument of destruction,
然后设陷阱 再一网打尽
trap them there, and then wipe them out.
简单得很 Ericka
It's simple, Ericka!
向我保证 在那之前你不会杀了Dracula
Now, promise me you won't try and kill Dracula.
呃 行吧
Ugh, fine!
- 我保证 - 保证什么
- I promise. - Promise what?
我保证我不会杀掉Dracula 可以了吧
I promise I won't try and kill Dracula. Okay?
呃
Ugh.
别担心 曾祖父 我不会试试能不能杀掉他
Don't worry, Great-Grandfather, I won't try and kill him…
我会直接杀了他
I will kill him.
∮ 今夜 ∮
∮ Tonight… ∮
∮ 我只想带你们嗨起来 ∮
∮ I just want to take you higher ∮
∮ 同志们 把你们的戒指甩向天际 ∮
∮ Put yo' pinky rings up to the moon ∮
- ∮小妞们 ∮ - ∮ 都愣着干嘛 ∮
- ∮ Girls ∮ - ∮ What y'all tryin' to do? ∮
∮ 闪耀着金光的魔法在空气中璀璨夺目 ∮
∮ 24-karat magic in the air ∮
∮ 贯穿你整个身体 ∮
∮ Head-to-toe ∮
嚯
Whew!
∮ 注意了 ∮
∮ Uh, look out ∮
- ∮ 呦呦重头戏来了 ∮ - ∮ 无敌重头戏 ∮
- ∮ Pop, pop, it's showtime ∮ - ∮ Showtime ∮
- ∮ 无敌重头戏 ∮ - ∮ 无敌重头戏 ∮
- ∮ Showtime ∮ - ∮ Showtime ∮
∮ 看看是谁回来了 ∮
∮ Guess who's back again ∮
- ∮ 不知道吗 ∮ - ∮ 告诉他们 ∮
- ∮ Oh, they don't know? ∮ - ∮ Go on, tell 'em ∮
- ∮ 还不知道吗 ∮ - ∮ 快告诉他们 ∮
∮ 等我们上场时一切都将揭晓 ∮
∮ I'll bet they know as soon as we walk in ∮
- ∮ 秀起来 ∮ - ∮ 古巴大链子 ∮
- ∮ Sho' 'nuff ∮ - ∮ I'm wearin' Cuban links ∮
- ∮ 最新款貂皮大衣 ∮ - ∮ 没错 ∮
- ∮ Designer'minks ∮ - ∮ Yeah ∮
∮ 别再看了 小心受打击 ∮
∮ Don't look too hard, might hurt yourself ∮
∮ 小心撞得遍体鳞伤 ∮
∮ Known to give the color red The blues ∮
∮ 都愣着干嘛呢 ∮
∮ Tell me whatcha tryin' to do ∮
∮ 闪耀着金光的魔法在空气中璀璨夺目 ∮
∮ 24-karat magic in the air ∮
呃
Ugh!
∮ 月亮 ∮
∮ Moon ∮
- ∮ 小妞们 ∮ - ∮ 都愣着干嘛 ∮
- ∮ Girls ∮ - ∮ What y'all tryin' to do? ∮
噢
Oh!
- ∮ 小妞们 ∮ - ∮ 都愣着干嘛 ∮
- ∮ Girls ∮ - ∮ What y'all tryin' to do? ∮
∮ 纯金的24K璀璨 ∮
∮ 24-karat… ∮
∮ 同志们 快把你们的戒指甩向天际 ∮
∮ Put yo' pinky rings up to the moon ∮
很有型噢 Dracula
Work it, Dracula.
你懂的
You know it.
唉哟 不错噢 Drac
Oh! Lookin' good, Drac!
还好啦 Frank
Feeling good, Frank.
看看你 帅得不行
Look at you, so fancy!
真的吗 谢谢夸奖
What? This? Please.
哇 打扮得让姑娘印象深刻 啊哈
Ooh! Dressed to impress, huh?
什么印象深刻 噢
"Impress"? Oh.
我需要让谁印象深刻吗
Who do I need to impress?
瞧 那不是Ericka船长吗
Hey, isn't that Captain Ericka?
噢 不不不不不不
Oh, no!
啊 什么 啊 噢
Uh, what? Eh, oh…
哎呀 看错了 不是她
Oops, no, not her.
噢哈哈哈哈 这也太好玩了
Ooh, that's good!
是很有趣哈
Very amusing.
对不起 Drac 我们从没见过你这样
Sorry, Drac. You know, it's just we've never seen you like this.
我知道
I know.
这事根本讲不通啊
It doesn't make any sense.
我们不可能心动两次的 这绝对不可能
You can't Zing twice, it's impossible!
但我确实心动了 所以现在该怎么办
But I did! So now what?
Mavis又会怎么想
And what about Mavis?
她希望你开心 不是吗
She wants you to be happy, right?
我确信她会顺其自然就接受了
I'm sure she'll go with the flow.
噢 不不不
Oh, no, no, no!
Mavis需要我 我还要保护她
Mavis needs me. She depends on me.
我得和家人待在一起
I need to be home with my family.
嘿 Murray家是在埃及 但你可是住在尼罗河畔啊
Hey, Murray here may be from Egypt, but you're the one in.
「顺其自然」
"da Nile."
你们懂我的意思吗
You guys get that?
嗷噢 你正好打到了我的
Ow! You hit me right in the…
Mavis！
Mavis!
闭嘴 不然我在梦里也饶不了你们
Don't say a word, or I'll haunt your dreams.
你玩得开心吗
Having fun?
当然了 你来了我现在更开心了
Oh, I'm having even more fun now that you're here.
爸爸 能和你一起出来旅行我觉得很幸运
You know, Dad, I feel really lucky to have this time with you.
一家人都在一起 这经历太珍贵了
All of us together, it's really special.
我也是 你个小机灵鬼
Me, too, spider monkey.
那现在你准备好迎接怪兽排球的挑战了吗
Now, are you ready for me to destroy you in monster ball?
哇噢 怪兽排球
Whoo-hoo! Monster ball!
来吧 Drac外公
Come on, Papa Drac!
安排上了
Bring it on!
我可是家里的游戏之王
For I am king of family fun!
哈哈 好了 准备好接球了吗
Ha-ha! All right! Who is ready to get pummeled?
我得提醒你一下
I got to warn you,
我可在Santa Cruz学校排球赛中 排名第二的队伍里练过
I played second-team coed intramural volleyball at Santa Cruz.
行啊 朋友 随你怎么说
Sure, pal. Whatever you say.
朋友们 请注意点我的发型
Everybody, just please watch the hair.
不要弄乱我的头发
Watch the hair!
噢 噢 噢 开始吧 让我们开始吧
Oh-ho-ho! Let's go! Let's do this!
噢太棒了 这比赛肯定有趣极了
Oh, my gosh, this is gonna be so much fun.
哈哈 准备好
Ha-ha! Get ready.
球来啦
Here comes the pain!
- 准备好 大力扣杀 - 别碰我头发别碰我头发
- Spike! - Not the hair!
哇噢
Whoa!
不不不不不
No, no, no!
噢耶
All right!
Ericka船长 甲板需要您
Captain Ericka, you are needed on deck.
下一站 永别Dracula
Next stop… Buh-bye, Dracula.
哈哈 看球 伙计们
Ha-ha! All right, baby!
噢看着吧 我能接住这个球
Oh, baby, I got this.
现在看向这里 怪兽们
Hey there, monsters.
哈
Huh?
耶 我说什么来着
Yeah! What'd I say!
我们即将抵达我们行程的第一站
We're arriving at our first destination.
水下火山
The underwater volcano!
所有人带好你们的潜水装备 准备开启
Everyone, grab your scuba gear and get ready to explore.
深海探险之旅吧
the wonders of the sea.
特别是你
Especially you,
Dracula伯爵
Count Dracula.
兄弟听到了吗 她看上你了
You see that, pal? She likes you.
噢 不不不
Oh, no, no, no.
这听起来她也心动得不行啊
That sounds like a Zing in full effect.
噢 不不不
Oh, no, no, no.
噢 就是 就是 就是
Oh, yes, yes, yes.
我来这儿就是享受天伦之乐的
I'm just here to have family fun.
家庭聚会 真呀么真有趣
Family, family, fun, fun.
嗯 我看看 放这里怎么样
Hmm, let's see. What about here?
各位请往这边走
Right this way, everyone.
欢迎来到水下王国的奇迹之一
Welcome to one of the true wonders of the underwater kingdom.
向您呈现Fuego火山
I give you Volcano del Fuego.
当地人称之为
Or, as the local sea life call it…
噢 多么可爱的一家人啊
Aw, what a cute family.
什么 才不是呢
What? No, it's not.
啊 坏蛋Dracula
Argh! Dracula bad!
Frank 我们才刚刚吃过
Frank, we just ate.
你居然又饿了
I can't believe you're hungry already.
我很抱歉 但是你知道是为什么吗
I'm sorry. You know what it is?
那都是因为我周围游满了海鲜
It's all… Just all that seafood just swimming around,
然后我一看见吃的就
and when I "see food…"
有点出息吧 我走了
Oh, man! I'm gone.
Oh！Dracula，Dracula，Dracula！
Oh! Dracula, Dracula, Dracula!
Dracula Dracula
Dracula, Dracula!
我明明离他那么近了 但感觉他像是在戏弄我一般
I get so close, but it's almost like he's teasing me.
我实在 忍无可忍了
I just, I can't stand it anymore.
我必须要得手
I have to get him!
知道嘛 水下火山看上去超级热
Boy, that underwater volcano looked hot.
嗯嗯
Mmm-hmm.
噢 嗨 Bob
Oh… Hi, Bob.
对了 我们刚刚答应你的 呃 现在去打乒乓球吧
Right. We promised you we'd play, uh, ping-pong now.
呃 Dennis 这位是谁
Um, Dennis? Who is this?
呃 这是我们的朋友 Bob
Uh, it's our friend, Bob.
- 说个嗨 Bob - 嗨 Bob
- Say hi, Bob. - "Hi, Bob."
好啦 去打乒乓球咯
Okay! Time to go play ping-pong.
- Drac！- Drac！
- Drac! - Drac!
嘿 伙计们 是哪里着火啦
Hey, boys, where's the fire?
呃 嗯 是Griffin 他
Oh, well, Griffin here, he…
- 他有话想和你说 - 我么 呃
- He has something to tell you. - Me? Uh…
噢 对 我手上被咬了一下 然后 因为 你懂的
Oh. Yeah, I got this bite on my hand, and since, you know,
你是这方面的专家 我想你帮我看看
you're a biting expert, I thought you could take a look.
- 当然 来这边 - 光线好一些
- Yeah. Come on over here. - The light is better.
好 吧
Okay…
好吧 到底怎么了
Okay, what is going on?
你们这些家伙正常的时候都够奇怪了 现在比平常还要奇怪
You guys are acting weirder than normal, and your normal is pretty weird.
你不会相信我听到什么了 但是…
You are not gonna believe what we heard, but…
∮ Ericka爱上了Drac ∮
∮ Ericka loves the Drac ∮
∮ 她对Drac的爱没个够 ∮
∮ She can't get enough of that Drac ∮
∮ 噢 耶 ∮
∮ Oh, yeah ∮
∮ Drac回来啦 ∮
∮ Drac is back ∮
∮ 他又心动啦 ∮
∮ He's got the Zing ∮
∮ 心动呀动 ∮
∮ The Zinga-Zing ∮
嘘 我告诉过你 我不想让Mavis不开心
Shh. I told you I don't want to upset Mavis.
你们都在说些什么啊
But what are you talking about?
好 听着 Frank饿了 这没什么稀奇的
Okay, well, see, Frank got hungry, so no surprise there…
然后我们游回船的时候发现 Erica对你赞不绝口呢
But we swam back to the ship, and we found Ericka raving about you.
兄弟 没了你她活不下去啦
She can't live without you, buddy.
是认真的
It's serious!
∮ 宝贝儿 让心动时刻来临 你无法抗拒 ∮
∮ You can't deny the Zing, baby ∮
Drac 这太棒了 你会对她开始行动吗
So, Drac, this is great. Are you gonna make a move on the captain, or what?
是这么打算的
Uh, yes.
- 也许吧 不行 - 呃
- Maybe? No. - Ugh.
这太突然了 我都不知道该从哪开始
It's been a while. I don't even know where to start.
这很简单啊 Drac 就找些小话题聊聊嘛
It's easy, Drac. Just make some small talk.
- 记得要微笑 - 要看着她的眼睛
- Remember to smile. - Look into her eyes.
- 随意一点 - 风趣幽默一些
- Keep it casual. - Say something funny.
问问她 她的身体部位都是哪里来的
Ask her where her parts are from.
噢 夸夸她的缠身布很好看
Oh, and say that her wrappings look nice.
- 你喜欢住棺材吗 - 夸她就好
- "Do you like coffins?" - Compliment her.
- 夸她脖子看上去诱人好吃 - 她来啦
- "Your neck looks delicious." - Here she comes.
好啦 Drac 加油
Okay, Drac, hit it.
你诱人的脖子被缠身布裹在一个漂亮的棺材里
Your delicious neck wrappings are in a nice coffin.
你要看看我的身体吗
Would you like to see my parts?
好啊 我十分愿意跟你约会
Yes, I'd love to go out with you.
啊 什么
Ay! What?
什么
What?
酒吧 今晚12点
Cantina. Midnight.
不要迟到噢
Don't be late.
喔
Whew!
真险啊
That was a close one.
- 等一下 别跑 Tinkles 别跑 - 等等 Tinkles 回来
- Wait! Stop it, Tinkles, stop! - Wait, Tinkles. Come back.
- Tinkles 别跑 - 等一下
- Tinkles, stop! - Wait!
不要 不要 不要
No, no, no!
Tinkles 不要这样
Tinkles, stop!
我被发现啦
I've been found!
你永远都不会抓到我的 怪兽
You'll never get me, monster!
嘘 Tinkles 停下 嘘 嘘
Shh! Tinkles, stop. Shh! Shh!
各位 我们即将抵达下一站 浪漫荒岛
Everybody, we are pulling up to our next stop, the Deserted Island.
是时候在沙滩上狂欢啦
It's time to get lost on the beach,
我们希望你们玩得开心 放松身心
and we hope you'll find yourself some fun and relaxation.
喔喔 沙滩时刻
Whoo-hoo! Beach time!
Johnny 你去安置好所有东西
Johnny, you go set everything up.
还有爸爸 你去排队拿冰沙
And, Dad, you go get in line for the snow cones.
其实 我在想你和Johnny
You know, actually, I was thinking you and Johnny.
应该多花些时间呆在一起
should spend some time together.
你上次是怎么说的来着 呃 约会之夜
What do you call it again? Eh, date night?
约会之夜
Date night?
- 那你又打算做什么呢 - 我打算
- What are you gonna do? - Well, I thought.
和大伙们借着这次机会
me and the guys would take this opportunity.
与Dennis共度美好时光
to spend some quality time with Dennis.
噢 好吧 是个不错的主意
Oh. Okay. That's a great idea.
来吧 Johnny 约会之夜
Come on, Johnny. Date night.
哒哒哒哒 约会之夜
Duh-duh-duh-duh-date night!
好了 去拿吧
Okay, here you go!
- 真棒 - 这次换我扔
- Good girl! - I got this one.
那是什么
What was that?
听上去好像是我们的孩子们
It sounds like our children.
- 还真是我们的孩子们 跑啊 - 快跑
- It is our children! Run! - Run!
救命 来个人 请救救我
Please! Help! Someone!
找一下他们父母
Get the parents!
Frank 来帮我在背上擦点防晒霜
Frank? Would you rub some moonscreen on my back.
免得被月亮晒伤
before I get burned?
等一下 亲爱的
Wait one second, honey.
那些孩子把我埋在沙里了
You know, the kids buried me in the sand.
嗯 谢谢你 亲爱的
Mmm. Thanks, honey.
- 再来一杯吗 - 当然
- Shall we have another? - Sure.
- 感觉真好 - 干了吧
- Sounds good. - Straight up.
这个地方是不是很棒
Isn't this place amazing?
喔呜 菜单是装在瓶子里的
Whoa! The menu is in a bottle!
太天才啦 是不是棒极了 亲爱的
Genius! Isn't that awesome, honey?
什么 噢 对不起
What? Oh, sorry.
我在想着我爸爸
I was just thinking about my dad.
你不觉得他最近奇奇怪怪的吗
Don't you think he's acting weird lately?
不觉得啊 除了十分迷恋船长之外
Not really. Besides having a huge crush on the captain.
- 你说什么 - 没错的
- What? - Oh, yeah.
爱情的小船肯定会再次扬帆了
The Love Boat is definitely making another run.
不可能 他是
No way. He's…
他可是我老爸啊
He's my dad.
是吧 我懂 是有些奇怪
I know, right? It's weird.
即使是现在 当我父母亲亲时 我都还是闭着眼睛的
When my parents kiss, I still close my eyes.
我只是从未想过 爸爸会和妈妈以外的人在一起
I guess I never thought about him with anyone besides my mom.
即使这样 你还是可以接受的 是吧
You're cool with it, though, right?
当然 我希望他幸福
Of course. I want him to be happy.
绝对的
Totally.
晚上好 我的朋友
Buenas noches, mi amigo.
你有 「饮料」 可以 解我的渴吗
Have you a beverage to quench me of my parchment?
有 当然有 Chupacabra先生
Yes, of course, Mr. Chupacabra.
十分感谢
Muchas gracias.
你真迷人
You look ravishing.
噢
Oh.
啊 谢谢 我只是
Uh, thank you. I just…
噢
Oh.
那 唔…
So, um…
Ericka船长姓什么呢
Does Captain Ericka have a last name?
啊 噢 啊…
Uh, oh, uh…
噢 Guacamole （鳄梨酱）
Oh, guacamole!
「Ericka Guacamole」？
"Ericka Guacamole"?
还真洋气
That's so international.
不 我们应该一起尝尝鳄梨酱
No. Guacamole for us to share.
噢 今晚的月色多美
Oh, how beautiful is that full moon tonight?
看 就在你身后
Look. Right behind you.
嗯 这里的食物真是让人食指大动
Mmm! The food here is to die for.
我的天啊 好多鳄梨酱
Holy moly, that was a lot of guacamole.
你还好吗
Are you feeling all right?
- 我很好 怎么了 - 没什么
- Totally fine. Why? - No reason.
噢
Oh…
鳄梨酱里一定有大蒜
There must have been garlic in the guacamole.
噢 不
Oh, no.
对你来说是不是很致命啊
Isn't that deadly for you?
不 不 不 只是我
No, no, no. It's just that I'm…
大蒜不耐受
Garlic intolerant.
是你放的吗
Was that you?
哇噢
Whoo!
噢 耶
Oh, yeah!
海豚冲浪
Dolphin surfing!
哇噢
Whoa!
嗨 妈妈 嗨 爸爸
Hi, Mama. Hi, Papa.
嘿 嘿
Hey-hey.
噢 嘿
Oh! Hey there.
- 爸爸 - 嗨
- Papa. - Hidey-ho!
嗨
Hi.
我爸爸也在这里吗
Is my dad in there, too?
别担心 我在这儿呢 「给我血 给我血”
Don't worry, I'm over here. Bleh, bleh-bleh.
没有 外公不在这里 他去约会了
No, Papa Drac's not here. He's on his date.
约会
Date?
请原谅我
Please, forgive me,
我只是太紧张了
I'm just very nervous.
你要知道
You see,
自从我妻子去世后 我就再也没有约过会了
I haven't had a date since my wife died.
你女儿那时候多大啊
How old was your daughter?
她还是个婴儿
She was just an infant.
做一个单身父亲真的不容易
It was hard being a single dad,
但我尽力了
but I did my best.
我也从没见过我母亲
I never knew my mother, either.
还有父亲
Or my father.
噢 我很抱歉
Oh, I'm so sorry.
那谁抚养你长大呢
Who raised you?
我的曾祖父
My great-grandfather.
我几乎是在这艘船上长大的
I basically grew up on this ship.
所以你现在是船长了呀
That's why you're a captain.
是的 这就是我的一切
Yeah. It's all I've ever known.
家里人期望我成这个样子
It was just expected.
你懂的 家庭嘛
You know, a family thing.
我明白 家庭就是一切
I understand, family is everything.
你必须在尊重过去的同时
You have to honor the past.
创造未来
But we make our own future.
- 爸爸 - Mavis
- Dad? - Mavis!
- 嗯 - Johnny
- Mmm. - Johnny!
我刚刚和Ericka船长在讨论酒店行业
Captain Ericka and I were just discussing the hospitality industry.
只是工作的事情
You know, just work stuff.
你现在在工作吗
You're working now?
你本该来这儿度假啊
This is supposed to be a vacation.
家庭旅行
A family vacation.
我还有一些 船长的事情 要去处理
I should really go do captain-y things.
爸爸 你说过你会和Dennis呆在一起的
Dad, you said you were gonna spend time with Dennis.
Dennis。Dennis？Dennis
Dennis. Dennis? Dennis.
噢 你说得对 那孩子去哪儿了
Oh! Yeah, you're right. Where is that kid?
Denisovich 你应该待在我身边的
Denisovich? You're supposed to be with me.
来吧 孩子 现在是家庭时间
Come on now, kid, it's family time.
不要再藏了 Dennis
Quit hiding. Dennis?
怎么回事
What was that about?
你是说你爸爸的约会
You mean your dad's date?
这不是约会 这是 工作上的事情
It wasn't a date. It was work stuff.
嗯哼
Uh-huh.
我告诉你 Johnny
I'm telling you, Johnny,
我不信任那个女人
there is something about that woman I don't trust.
但是你希望你爸爸幸福 对吗
But you want your dad to be happy, right?
是
Yes.
但是不能是和她在一起
Just not with her.
嗯 喔呼呼
Mmm. Whoo-hoo-hoo!
振作点 亲爱的
Heads up, honey.
这个鳄梨酱里都是大蒜噢
This guac is loaded with garlic.
大蒜
Garlic?
真是动听的曲调呀 亲爱的
Aw! That was a cute toot, honey.
- 我们一整晚都在玩耶 - 我们也要玩一整个白天
- We've been up all night! - Let's stay up all day, too!
我们狂欢吧
Let's get wild!
- Ericka！-什么鬼
- Ericka! - What?
你刚去哪里了 姑娘
Just where have you been, young lady?
呃 在工作而已
Uh, doing work.
戴着那个吗
Wearing that?
你刚和他在一起 我知道
You were with him! I know it!
谁
Who?
谁 你心里知道是谁
"Who?" You know who!
你其实一直在背着我
You've been sneaking around my back.
又想偷偷地杀掉Dracula 是不是
trying to kill Dracula again, haven't you?
是又怎样 我现在可是个成年人
So what if I have? I am a grown woman!
我有权杀掉任何一个我想要的杀的人
I have the right to kill whoever I want.
这可不仅仅是你一个人的事情
It's not just about you.
你会破坏掉家族事业的
You could have ruined the legacy.
如果他发现你是谁怎么办
What if he discovered who you were?
我知道 我没想那么多 但他这个人不知怎么的
I know. I wasn't thinking. There's just something about him.
让我快疯了
that just drives me crazy!
我只是 我看到他 我想
I just, I see him, and I want to…
打他
Punch him?
呃 估计是吧
Uh… I guess.
我等不及想要解决他了
Just, I can't wait to get this over with.
别担心 不会太久了
Don't worry, it won't be long now.
一旦你拿到了无敌破坏乐谱
Once you recover the instrument of destruction,
就没人能阻止我们了
no one can stop us.
就连Dracula也不行
Not even Dracula!
- 噢 打扰了 - 间谍
- Oh. Excuse me. - Spies!
现在 赶快 趁还没有人来之前
Now, quickly, before someone comes!
请大家在甲板上集合
Everyone assemble on the forward deck.
我们已经到达了我们的目的地
We are arriving at our final destination.
从世界的深处
From the depths of creation,
这座伟大的城市将再次出现
the mighty city has risen once again.
世界上最伟大的
Home to the greatest monster civilization.
怪兽文明之乡
the world has ever known,
它优雅 精致 其艺术 文化远超罗马和雅典
far surpassing Athens and Rome in art, culture and sophistication.
为您介绍传说中失落的城市 亚特兰提斯
I give you the legendary lost city of Atlantis.
天啊 超级大海怪
It's a giant Kraken!
∮ 有一个地方你一定要去 ∮
∮ There's a place you've gotta be ∮
∮ 数千部落藏匿于海 ∮
∮ A thousand leagues beneath the sea ∮
∮ 它在等着我和你 ∮
∮ And it's waiting over here for you and me ∮
∮ 将要带你去旅行 ∮
∮ Gonna take you for a ride ∮
∮ 但首先你得先进来 ∮
∮ But first you've gotta come inside ∮
∮ 为今晚的派对做好准备 ∮
∮ Get ready, for the party's on tonight ∮
∮ 所以只要放松和放松 ∮
∮ So relax and just unwind ∮
∮ 把你的烦恼全都抛在脑后 ∮
∮ Leave your worries all behind ∮
∮ 为今晚的派对做好准备 ∮
∮ And get ready, for the party's on tonight ∮
欢迎来亚特兰蒂斯
Welcome to Atlantis!
∮ 所以 准备好 ∮
∮ So get ready ∮
∮ 准备好 ∮
∮ Ready ∮
噢
Oh!
∮ 派对时间到了 ∮
∮ It's party time ∮
噢 太刺激了
Ooh. I am so excited!
来吧
Come to Daddy!
- Oh - 28点
- Oh. - Twenty-eight black!
- 啊 - 不 你不想
- Ahhh! - Oh, no, you don't.
上一次你赌博输掉了一支手和一条腿
Last time you gambled, you lost an arm and a leg. Literally!
- 替换你的四肢… - 我再加到40
- Replacement limbs… - I'll raise you 40.
可不像以前那么容易啦
…aren't just lying around like they were in the old days.
所以 不准赌博
So, no gambling.
Frank！
Frank!
是的 亲爱的 我知道了 不赌博
Yes, dear! Got it! No gambling!
- Tinkles停下 - 等等
- Tinkles, stop. - Wait.
- 停下来 Tinkles停下来 - Ah 等下
- Stop it, Tinkles, stop. - Ah! Wait!
你们见到Mavis了吗 我得找到她
Have you guys seen Mavis? I have to find her.
怎么啦 出什么事了吗
Why? What's going on?
我想告诉她关于Ericka的事
I'm going to tell her about Ericka.
我不想再对我的女儿说谎了
I can't lie to my own daughter anymore.
她对我来说是世界上最重要的人了
She's the most important person in the world to me.
我必须告诉她真相
I have to tell her the truth.
但是 在这之前我得先和Ericka谈谈
Right after I talk to Ericka.
嘿
Hey.
好吧 我全都
All right, I'm all…
Frank 你知道自已在做什么吗
Frank, are you sure you know what you're doing?
放心吧 我全押
I got this. I'm all in.
Johnny 你看见我爸爸了吗
Johnny, have you seen my dad?
- 他有可能和 Bob在一起 - 他为什么会和Bob在一起
- Maybe he's with Bob. - Why would he be with Bob?
Bob是一个好人
Bob's a great guy.
- Oh 他在那 - 谁 Bob吗
- Oh, there he is. - Who? Bob?
他在那呀 嗨 Bob
There he is! Hi, Bob!
噢
Oh.
在那
There it is.
你救了我的命
You saved my life.
当然 我为什么不呢
Of course. Why wouldn't I?
我只是不相信 你会为了一个人类这么做
I just can't believe you would do that for a human.
人类 怪兽 有什么区别呢
Humans, monsters, what's the difference?
对 是的 说的对
Yeah, right. Right.
等下 你在这里做什么
Wait. What are you doing here?
呃 恩 你知道 吸血鬼能预见未来
Oh, uh… Well, you know, vampires can predict the future,
所以我知道你会需要我的帮助
so I knew you would need my help.
是嘛 以前怎么没听说过
Ha! Never heard that before.
啊 哈哈 这是众所周知的嘛
Oh, yeah, yeah, yeah. It's a well-known fact.
你又在这里做什么
What are you doing here?
噢 呃
Oh! Uh…
嗯 我来这里是为了拿那个东西
Well, I'm here to get that.
嗯 这是个传家宝
Yeah, it's a family heirloom.
是的 它本来掉到海里了 我的祖父 曾经
Yeah, it was lost at sea, and my great-grandfather is… Was!
一度很执着的想要找回它
Uh, was totally obsessed with getting it back.
所以 那个 谢谢你救了我的命 但是我自己可以
So, anywho, thanks for saving my life, but I can take it from…
要多加小心噢
Got to be a little more careful.
你能救我多少次呢
How many times can you save my life, right?
我不知道 大概每一次吧
I don't know. Every time?
真的吗 好吧
Really? Well, then…
啊 太神奇了
Ah, that was incredible.
噢 呃
Oh, uh…
你不是还要去取你的传家宝吗
Don't you want to get your family heirloom thingy?
对
Oh. Right.
拿到啦
Got it.
来 让我帮你拿掉吧
Oh, here, let me get that for you.
爸爸
Dad!
Mavis！
Mavis!
你在对我父亲做什么
What are you doing to my father?
等等 喂
Wait! Whoa. Whoa!
Mavis 停下 放她下来
Mavis, stop! Put her down!
不 她想要伤害你 你难道看不出来吗
No! She's trying to hurt you. Why can't you see that?
因为我
Because I…
因为我心动了
Because I Zinged.
什么
What?
我想我对Ericka动心了
I Zinged with Ericka.
不 这不可能是真的
No, that can't be true.
你只能有一次心动
You only Zing once.
我也曾这么以为
That's what I thought, too.
心动 什么是心动
"Zing"? What's a Zing?
噢 是怪兽的事情
Uh, well, it's a thing for monsters.
就是人类所说的 一见钟情
It's kind of like our "love at first sight."
什么 不 不 不 不可能
What? No. No, no, no.
- 你甚至都不了解我 - 暂时而已
- You don't even know me. - Well, not yet.
- 但我们正要 - 不 你不懂
- But we're just… - No, you don't understand.
我不能和你在一起
I can't be with you.
我永远不会和像你这样的人在一起
I could never be with someone like you.
我永远不会爱上
I could never be with.
一个怪兽
a monster.
爸 我很抱歉
Dad, I'm so sorry.
- 我 - 没关系
- I… - It doesn't matter.
你听见她说什么了
You heard what she said.
但是心动 不会错的
But a Zing never lies.
哈 你得手啦
Ha! You got it!
对
Yes.
现在 我们得到了无敌破坏乐谱
Now that we have the instrument of destruction,
我们将会完成家族的传承
our family legacy will be fulfilled.
但首先 我们得把他们引到一个舞会上
But first, we'll draw them in with a dance party!
我爱跳舞
I love to dance.
Frank 帮我拉下拉链
Frank, could you zip me up?
我们要迟到了
We're gonna be late.
你从哪搞到的这个
Where did you get those?
额 这事说来有趣
Uh, see, here's the funny thing.
我赌博把手输掉了 但没什么大不了
I lost my hands gambling, but… It's no big deal!
看 我在海鲜自助台上找到了这些
Look, I got these from the seafood buffet.
瞧瞧这个 我夹 我夹 我夹 夹 夹
Look at this. Clickety-click, click, clack, clack, click, click.
我还蛮喜欢这对钳子 很喜欢
I kind of like 'em. I like 'em.
嗯 嗯 嗯
Mmm! Mmm! Mmm.
哎 哎
Mmm. Mmm.
啊哈
A-ha!
我觉得派对在这边
Ah, I guess the party's this way.
哇噢
Whoo!
Whoa!
哇
Wow.
让我们燥起来吧
Let's get this party started right!
- 哇呜 - 来吧
- Whoo-hoo! - All right!
什么
What?
哈
Huh?
我以为他们说派对在这边
I thought they said the party was this way.
贝壳里的DJ
DJ in a clamshell?
真是羡慕 嫉妒 恨
I'm so jealous.
我不敢相信 我爸居然爱上了一个想杀他的人
I can't believe my dad Zinged with someone who's trying to kill him.
是啊 真爱的确会让人做出些疯狂的事
Yeah, the Zing makes you do crazy things.
真的吗 Johnny？
Really, Johnny?
最重要的是 你要明白 爱是一个永恒之谜
What's most important to understand is that love is an infinite enigma.
远远超出了我们的理解范围
that is beyond our understanding.
曾经 你我是两个独立的人 两个世界的人
You and I were two halves, a world apart.
但是冥冥之中 在命运的指引下
But then we followed the strands of destiny.
我们相遇了
and were brought together.
你我融为了一体
And our halves made one whole.
但是如果她和他…
But what if she and he…
你要放下消极看法 审视内心
You must release all the negativity and look within.
心与心的结合 是分不开的
Your bond is unbreakable.
你说得对 亲爱的 哇噢
You're right, honey. Wow.
谢了
Thanks.
哇爸爸 你听起来好聪明啊
Whoa, you sounded pretty smart, Dad.
噢 这些嘛 是我小时候最喜欢的
Oh, that? Yeah, it was just the philosophy.
中国武术电视节目里的少林功夫大师
of Sifu Sing from my favorite TV show when I was a kid,
所传授的哲学
Kung Fu Shaolin Monk Master.
总之 接着来跳舞吧
Anyways, let's get back to dancing!
酷
Cool.
爸 你一定要和Ericka谈谈
Dad? You have to talk to Ericka.
- 什么 - 我知道
- What? - I know.
我之前说的话
I know what I said before,
可能我有一丢丢反应过度了
but maybe I overreacted a teensy bit.
我只是害怕失去你
It's just the thought of losing you.
什么 你在说什么啊 失去我
What? What are you talking about, losing me?
当然啊 要是你结婚了
Well, obviously, after you get married,
你就会呆在这艘船上 然后去环游世界了
you're gonna live on the ship and travel around the world…
噢噢噢 等等 Mavis
Whoa, whoa, whoa. Slow down, Mavis.
有两件事是我可以向你保证的
There are two things I can promise you.
第一 没有什么能把我和你 还有咱们这个家分开
One, nothing can ever take me from you and all my family.
第二 我也绝不会住在一艘船上
Two, I will never live on a boat.
你永远是我的可爱小蛛蛛
You're my cute little tarantula.
我怎么可能离开你呢
How could I ever leave you?
好的 现在 快去找她谈谈吧
Now, seriously, go talk to her.
我不能去 你也听见她说什么了
I can't. You heard what she said,
她不可能跟我这样的吸血鬼在一起
she could never be with someone like me.
不 爸爸 你现在不完整
No, Dad. You're just a half,
你必须听从命运的安排 找到另一半 成为一个永恒的整体
and you have to follow your destiny to find an infinite whole.
你这语气 真像Johnny
You sound like Johnny.
起码 你不能否认你的心动
Point is, you can't deny a Zing.
怪兽 人类 独角兽
Monster, human, unicorn…
这些都没关系
It doesn't matter.
所以 去找她吧 就是现在
So go to her! Now!
好的 我这就去
Okay. I'm on it.
嘿 朋友 你不能在这
Hey, man, you're not allowed up here.
我的DJ棚可不是谁都能进的
The DJ booth is a sacred space.
不 Tinkles 安静
No. Tinkles, quiet.
噢 这是谁啊
Who is this?
嘿 我知道你认得我 你最大的敌人
Ha! I know you recognize me, your greatest rival.
嗯 噢 是的
Hmm. Oh, right.
你不就是机场下面那家假日酒店的老板吗
You own that Holiday Inn down by the airport.
不 是我 Abraham Van Helsing
No! It is I, Abraham Van Helsing.
Van Helsing？
Van Helsing?
都过这么多年了
After all these years?
你看起来不咋地啊
You look awful.
你的嘴总是这么讨厌
Always with the quick insults.
无所谓 反正它会让你闭嘴的
Well, this will shut you up.
还有所有的怪兽
And all monsters.
哈 这个 不就是Ericka的传家宝吗
Eh, huh? That's just Ericka's family heirloom thingy.
我的好曾孙女 Ericka
Good one, Ericka.
Ericka？
Ericka?
你这个傻瓜
You fool.
她可不光是船长呢
Not only is she the ship's captain,
她还碰巧是
but she also happens to be…
等等 你来告诉他
Wait. You tell him.
我是他的曾孙女
I'm his great-granddaughter.
我是Ericka Van Helsing
I'm Ericka Van Helsing.
我就知道她不对劲
I knew there was something wrong with her.
但是
But…
事情是这样的 我
See, what happened…
既然我们都在这了
Now that we're all caught up,
那就一起受死吧
let's get back to the dying.
瞧啊 这是能灭掉所有怪兽的宝物
Behold, the key to the demise of all monsters.
拭目以待啊
Let's see.
好了
Right… Okay.
听听这旋律
Listen to the melody.
是你们的催命符
of your destruction.
噢 瞧瞧这个小玩意
Ooh, what's this little doodad do?
耶
Yeah!
嘿 看啊 是海怪
Hey, look! It's the Kraken.
所有人 马上撤离
Everybody out! Now!
没路了 大家后退
We're trapped! Everybody back!
耶
Yay!
宝贝
Baby!
爸爸
Papa!
这一切该结束了
This has to stop now!
Drac 别
Drac, no!
啊
Ah!
爸爸
Dad!
Mavis！
Mavis!
不朽的Dracula 你的死期到了
Time for the immortal Dracula to die.
爸爸
Dad!
不
No!
Ericka！
Ericka!
Bob 快来帮忙
Bob! Help!
叫我吗
Huh?
是Tinkles吗
Tinkles?
Dennis
Dennis.
噢不 Bob就是Tinkles吗
Oh, no. Bob is Tinkles?
他怎么来的
How did he get here?
但感谢上帝 还好他来了 你看
But thank goodness he did, 'cause look!
你不能这样做
You can't do this!
你对怪兽有误解
You're wrong about monsters!
Dracula 他救过我的命
Dracula… He saved my life.
你说什么
What?
我非常抱歉 Drac
I'm so sorry, Drac.
我之前一直在找机会杀了你
I was trying to kill you this whole time,
但后来我发现自己犯了大错
but then I realized how wrong I was.
这一切都做错了
How wrong all of this is.
不知不觉中 我
And then I…
对你心动了
I Zinged.
什么「心动」 你在说些什么
"Zing"? What's a Zing?
这是怪兽界的说法
It's a monster thing.
你不会明白的
You wouldn't understand.
类似「真爱」这种说法
It's like true love.
爱吗
Love?
好吧 我想 这个家族事业由我来终结吧
Well, I guess the legacy ends with me.
唔 真是个尴尬的结局
Hmm, that's an awkward ending.
那可不行
Nope!
是时候开始新的传承了
It's time to start a new legacy.
怪兽与人类之间的传承
A monster-human legacy.
想都别想
No!
Drac醒醒 Van Helsing的音乐正在控制那个巨大的章鱼
Drac! Van Helsing's beats are controlling the giant octopus thingy.
要说我有什么讨厌的东西 那就是邪恶的DJ
If there's one thing I hate, it's an evil DJ.
我们需要正能量
We need positive energy!
准备来一场DJ之间的对决吧
Get ready for a DJ battle!
你随身都带着那些装备的吗
You just carry all that stuff around with you?
一日为DJ 终身为DJ
Once a bar mitzvah DJ, always a bar mitzvah DJ.
我们要用美好之音来战胜他的邪恶之声
We're gonna use good music to defeat his evil music.
- 你说啥 - 相信我 我懂音乐
- What? - Trust me, I know the tunes,
但是你拥有魔力
but you've got the power.
好勒 就这样
All right. Okay.
第一首歌就要燃爆全场
Opening song needs to be off the shizak.
耶 搞定 就放这首
Ooh, got it. Play this!
∮ 我接收到了幸福的感应 ∮
∮ I'm picking up good vibrations ∮
∮ 因为她令我激动不已 ∮
∮ She's giving me excitations ∮
- ∮ 多么美好 ∮ - ∮ 这样的感觉向我袭来 ∮
- ∮ Good ∮ - ∮ I'm picking up ∮
∮ 幸福的感觉 ∮
∮ Good vibrations ∮
∮ 因为她令我 ∮
∮ She's giving me ∮
∮ 激动不已 ∮
∮ Excitations ∮
∮ 多么美好 ∮
∮ Good, good, good ∮
∮ 幸福的感觉 ∮
∮ Good vibrations ∮
∮ 因为她令我 ∮
∮ She's giving me… ∮
什么鬼噪音
What is that noise?
∮ 我接收到了幸福的感应 ∮
∮ I'm picking up good vibrations ∮
∮ 她令我激动不已 ∮
∮ She's giving me excitations ∮
哇噢 我喜欢这首
Wow! I like this one.
感觉很棒
This feels good.
∮ 我们心灵相通 ∮
∮ Good vibrations ∮
大傻蛋
The fool.
喔喔 他的音乐太强大了
Whoa! His music is too powerful!
我们需要一些更正能量的歌曲
We're gonna need something even more positive.
就是现在 Drac
Now, Drac!
∮ 不必担忧 ∮
∮ So don't worry ∮
∮ 快乐一点 ∮
∮ Be happy ∮
∮ Don't worry ∮
- 你确定吗 - 歌词寓意不错
- Really? - It has a nice message.
∮ 不必担忧 ∮
∮ Don't worry ∮
∮ 快乐一点 ∮
∮ Be happy ∮
我已经受够了这些乱七八糟的声音
I've had enough of this nonsense!
Johnny 我们需要的是最能洗脑的音乐
Johnny, we need the most brain-dominating,
要全宇宙历史上最能打动人的歌
toe-tappinating song in the history of all the universe.
快啊 那首歌到底在哪
Come on. Where is it?
我也不知道啊
I don't know!
这里实在有太多歌曲了
There's too many choices.
不 等等
No, wait!
在这里
This is it.
这是什么
What the…
呃 这歌 真不怎么样
Boy, that stinks.
起作用啦
It's working!
嘿 Johnny选的老调音乐打败了邪恶音乐
Hey, Johnny's corny music is defeating the evil music.
我有点喜欢它了
I kind of like it.
嗷
Ooh!
不
No!
哎呀 哎 嗷
Argh! Ahhh! Whoo!
我被这节奏给洗脑了
I'm a slave to the rhythm!
不
No!
Drac 你做什么
Drac, what are you doing?
你不能心中永远充满仇恨
You got to be greater than the haters!
哈
Huh?
为什么
Why?
为什么 在我做了那么多伤害你的事情之后
Why, after everything,
你却还要救我
would you save my life?
因为从本质上来说我们都是一样的
Because basically we are all the same.
爪子或手 两只眼睛或者三只眼睛
Claws or hands, two eyes or three eyes.
- 绿皮肤 - 没皮肤
- Green skin. - No skin.
- 易怒的 - 聪明的
- Prickly. - Brainy.
对不起
I'm sorry.
真恶心
Ew.
你真了不起
You are amazing.
看我呀 Dennis 看我呀
Look at me, Dennis. Look at me.
来吧 你不能否认那种感觉噢
Come on, you can't deny it.
不 我还是个孩子
No! I'm too young to Zing!
好吧 我感觉自己现在有点傻
Well, I feel kind of silly now.
几十年来我一直在追捕你们
Heh. For decades I have hunted your kind,
迫害你们
persecuted you.
我唯一能做的就是补偿你们
The only thing I can do to make it up to you is.
给你们
give you.
30%的退款
a 30% refund.
少扯淡
Preposterous!
啊 好吧
Oh, all right.
全额退款
Full refund.
Wayne Wanda 你们怎么了
Wayne, Wanda, what happened to you guys?
嗯 我们 好像在游轮上都没见到你们
Yeah, we, like, hardly saw you on the cruise.
是啊 我知道
Yeah, I know.
我们被打了镇定剂 大部分时间都被锁在壁橱里
We got tranquilized and spent most of the trip locked in a closet.
我们打算下次假期再预定一次这个旅行
We're gonna book it again for the holidays.
你好 办理入住吗
Hi. Checking in?
是的 谢谢你
Yes. Thank you.
好的 我已经为您准备好了一间房
Great. I have a room all ready for you.
嘿 哥们 你能帮我打开吗
Hey, buddy, would you mind?
当然可以 哥们
Sure thing, pal.
好了 怎么了 神神秘秘的
Okay, what's going on, sneaky pants?
额 其实也没什么
Oh, nothing.
只不过 我想确保没有人可以打扰我们
It's just, I wanted to make sure nobody would bother us.
喔 为什么
Oh! Why?
你是要吸我的血吗 「给我血 给我血”
Are you going to suck-a my blood? Bleh, bleh-bleh.
不是
No.
我想问你
I was going to ask you.
你是否愿意嫁给我
if you would marry me.
怎么样 你觉得呢
Well? What do you say?
你愿意嫁给我吗
Will you marry me?
我 我
I… I…
Woobee deeba doobee？
Woobee deeba doobee?
什么
Wha…
我的意思是 我
I mean, I… woobee doobeedee?
她说了什么
What did she say?
额 我不太确定
Uh… I'm not sure.
我愿意
Yes!